Guide to the Radical Philosophy Association Photographs and Slides PHOTOS.272
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Radical Philosophy Association Photographs and Slides
1990; 1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Radical Philosophy Association
PHOTOS.272
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
The Radical Philosophy Association (RPA) is an international organization that was founded in 1982 to oppose capitalism, racism, sexism, homophobia, disability discrimination, pollution, and authoritarianism by drawing upon a variety of radical traditions including phenomenology, Marxism, anarchism, post-structuralism, post-colonial theory and environmentalism. This collection contains color photographs and slides that document two trips to Cuba taken by members of RPA in May 1990 and May/June 1992. RPA members toured the country, in particular its academic institutions, and participated in an academic conference focusing Marxism in Cuba.
Scope and Contents Note
The Radical Philosophy Association (RPA) Images Collection contains color slides and photographs of Robert A. Stone's May 1990 and May/June 1992 visits to Cuba with fellow members of the RPA. The collection includes: one slide carousel with approximately 140 slides and accompanying slide show script in English and Spanish; two sets of 4" x 6" color photographs with corresponding negatives dated May 24, 1990; and thirteen boxes of slides all dated May 1990 and May/June 1992 of which seven slide boxes are labeled. Most of the photographs and slides are from the May 1990 trip, which includes images of Cuba's architecture, the Lenin School, Universidad de Matanzas "Camilo Cienfuegos," and the proceedings of a conference in which members of the RPA probably participated. Photograph and slide captions suggest that conference's subject dealt with Marxist and communist theory in Cuba.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Related Archival Materials
Radical Philosophy Association Records (TAM.466)
Historical/Biographical Note
Founded in 1982, the Radical Philosophy Association (RPA) is an international organization whose mission is to oppose capitalism, racism, sexism, homophobia, disability discrimination, pollution, and authoritarianism by drawing upon a variety of radical traditions including phenomenology, Marxism, anarchism, post-structuralism, post-colonial theory and environmentalism. Its efforts center on conferences and publications. The RPA also publishes the journal Radical Philosophy Review.
Robert A. Stone is a member of RPA and has taught philosophy at institutions including Long Island University in New York.
Arrangement
The archivist imposed no order on this collection. Its original arrangement was maintained. The collection consists of one series.
I. Radical Philosophy Association Images.
Custodial History
The Alternative Press Center held these photographs and slides until 2009 when it donated them to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. The Radical Philosophy Association allowed the Tamiment Library/Wagner Labor Archives to take possession of these items in 2009 and sent additional materials in 2010. These donations were split into two collections: The Radical Philosophy Association Images Collection (PHOTOS.272) and Radical Philosophy Association Records Collection (TAM.466).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Radical Philosophy Association, 2009. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2012.055 and NPA.2009.014.
Communism -- Cuba.; Philosophy |x Political aspects.; Color slides.; Philosophers |x Societies, etc.; Color photographs.; Philosophers |x Political activity.; Cuba.; Cuba |x Tours.; Education -- Cuba.; Communism |z Cuba |x History |v Sources.; Radical Philosophy Association; Jones, Richard A.
- "Pix in Cuba"., circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Programa De Trabajo De Las Comisiones" [including Slide Carousel Script]., May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "1st & last & rejected shots"., circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "1 First & Last Pix"., May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "1st Havan[a] shots"., May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "CUBA 5/11/90 – 5/22/90" (Slide Carousel)., May 1990 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_c3bdaf7ac62d39d5e5b5e84b0187c60d)
- "3. 200 ASA 36; Bus ride with Eduardo Garcia from Hotel El Prendentz [sp?] through Havana to Havana Vieja, afternoon of Sunday, May 13, 1990" (Slide Box). (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_8f63647c52b2fc937357eb131b4d5a5c)
- "4. 200 ASA 36; START: La Bodeguita Del Medio after ariving at Machurrucutu [sp?] Hotel, Sunday evening May 13 (or 14?), 1990. End: Alberto Fraga & Emilio Ichikawa, May 16, 1990 at conference" (Slide Box). (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_64d9bfdc4b9959131331e40b140cc422)
- "5. 400 ASA 36; START: Papers by Olga Fernandez, Pat Mills & Elsie Plain Wed., May 16 (AM?) ENDS: Arrival at Lenin School Friday, May 18." [1990] (Slide Box). (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_541e31860954082febdcca4a4511fea4)
- "6. 200 ASA 36; Lenin School & Last day of conference 5/18/90" (Slide Box)., May 18, 1990 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_1986e7b67c359dd30867c24265ae130f)
- "7. 400 ASA 36; STATE: Party after last day of conference Friday, May 18, 1990 END: Sandino loop, Saturday, May 19, mid-day." [1990] (Slide Box)., May 19, 1990 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_5572b9c395077c929549d7c96dd4c6d7)
- "8. 100 ASA 36; END Visit to Matanzas Monday May 21 START Evening w. Marilyn & Lino [sp?] Saturday 19th" [1990] (Slide Box)., May 1990 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_e4880495d403a40155200730b3e66feb)
- "9. 100 ASA 36; START: Entering U. of Matanzas, 12:30 or so PM Monday, May 21, 1990. End: Thompson's in Ingiaterra Lobby, Lunch, Tuesday, May 22, 1990" ( Slide Box)., May 1990 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_02b540f9ac3e6c65da494d422a9ef61f)
- "5/29" [1992] (Slide Box)., May 29, 1992 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_6d2d34aff0df4657601910f29cfc439b)
- "CUBA 6/92, Opening Ceremony 6/5, CUBA '92" (Slide Box)., Jun 1992
- "6/8" [1992] (Slide Box)., Jun 8, 1992 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_adc6507b67b1e36d0c1eacb4f9672747)
- "Trip to Varadero 6/10" [1992] (Slide Box)., Jun 10, 1992 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_df2fa6d7fd6a8f414acc0bff4dc9708d)
- "6/10" [1992] (Slide Box)., Jun 10, 1992 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_dc6c9369e2d75198d7a688b8997e5d36)
- "6/11" [1992] (Slide Box)., Jun 11, 1992 (Box 1, Carton data_value_missing_1f81680f9a48a256504f4cedda123acb)